Todd A. Murphy

I am currently an Information Technology major with a Specialization in Network and Information Security. I am very experienced with electronics, computers and especially networking. In my free time, I enjoy designing circuits, printing them onto circuits boards and soldering components just so I can have another smart device controlled by Siri. As I continue my studies at NJIT, I plan on acquiring a





Tam44@njit.edu



(609) 501-5040



linkedin.com/in/tmurphy605



Sewell, NJ

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

New Jersey Institute of Technology Newark, NJ Expected Graduation: May 2020

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE =

Linux System Admin & Hardening Intern

Lockheed Martin

June 2018 – August 2018

Moorestown, NJ

- Responsible for hardening Red Hat Enterprise Linux up to DoD standards
- Responsible for creating and managing user accounts on new systems
- Experienced in racking and installation of new racks and servers

Resident Assistant

New Jersey Institute of Technology

August 2018 - Present

Newark, NJ

- Facilitate the academic, social and personal adjustment of students at the residence halls and at the University
- Responsible for enforcing policies of the University to the residents

Teacher's Assistant

New Jersey Institute of Technology

January 2018 – Present

Newark, NJ

- Class: IT114 Advanced Programming for Information Technology (JAVA)
- Assistant to the Teacher in all aspects such as: student help, grading and
- Held office hours for 10 hours a week, outside of class, for extra help

Technician

NJIT Media Services

Fall 2016 - Present

Newark, NJ

- Delivered and assembled all computer, sound and video related hardware for special events
- Experienced in troubleshooting technical problems, especially under pressure

Stagehand

I.A.T.S.E. Local 8

September 2014 – June 2018

Philadelphia, PA

- Responsible for all behind-the-scenes tech during live shows
- · Operated many sound consoles, lighting consoles, and spotlights
- Experienced in being a backstage coordinator

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE =

John O. Mosely Leadership School

Sigma Alpha Epsilon

July 2017

February 2018

Phoenix, Arizona

• Explored leadership abilities, learned new skills and interacted with interesting undergraduates and alumni from around the Realm of Sigma



Province Rho-Eta Leadership School

Sigma Alpha Epsilon

West Chester, Pennsylvania

• Explored new leadership abilities, received guidance on pressing issues and conversed with national members of Sigma Alpha Epsilon

AFFILIATIONS =

President & Webmaster

Sigma Alpha Epsilon Fraternity

Spring 2018 - Present

Treasurer

Sigma Alpha Epsilon Fraternity

Spring 2017 - Spring 2018

SOFTWARE -

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Fusion 360
- Word, Excel, PowerPoint
- Unity
- Android Studio
- Xcode
- Wireshark
- Remedy
- Experienced in Linux, macOS & Windows

COMPUTER LANGUAGES =

- Bash
- **JSON**
- **JAVA**
- HTML & CSS
- Python
- **JavaScript**
- Swift
- PHP
- Arduino
- SQL

PERSONAL PROJECTS '

DIY HomeKit Enabled LED's

Siri-enabled lights from scratch.

DIY Automatic Door Opener

Wi-Fi electric strike door circuit.

Sigma Alpha Epsilon – NJIT Website

Designed saenjit.com

WEBSITES





HTTP://TODDAMURPHY.ME